RENESH MADHAVAN

A-22-06, Alam Sanjung Apartment, Jalan Budiman 22/3, Seksyen 22, 40300 Shah Alam Selangor.

Mobile: +6019-655 5584

E-mail: renesh.madhavan@gmail.com



SUMMARY

14 years of total working experience in Human Resource and Logistics, with diversified skills of management, client relations, human resources, recruiting, and administrative support. An energetic team leader and motivator, able to communicate effectively with people from all ages and backgrounds, to work collaboratively to resolve problems and achieve organizational objectives.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

2016 – Present E2S Security Services Sdn Bhd, Nilai Operations Senior Officer

- Oversee operations in a safe, secure, efficient and cost-efficient manner that complies with the company policy, OSHA, DOE & etc
- Managing day-to-day operations and administration of the security assignments all over the country
- Ensure that all Health & Safety policies, procedures, rules and regulations are adhered to and are regularly reviewed, updated and communicated.
- To develop and review policies and procedures.
- Conduct market research and analysis on guarding services.
- Establish and maintain relationship with clients
- Prepare monthly and daily reports on operations

2015 – 2016 SMPC Industries, Klang HR and Safety Officer

- Ensure Health & Safety policies, procedures, rules and regulations are adhered to and are regularly reviewed, updated and communicated.
- Ensure that safety inspections are carried out, fire drills and fire alarms are correctly reported, safety inspections, risk assessments and lone working procedures are managed and employees are aware of their responsibilities.
- Ensure physical condition of warehouse by planning and implementing new design layouts, inspecting equipment, issuing work orders for repair and requisitions for replacement.
- Conduct and arrange regular trainings to workers to improvise working skills and productivity.
- Provide regular reports to the Human Resources Manager, Board of Directors/Senior Management Team on relevant health and safety activities.
- Conduct regular meetings with the Board of Directors/Senior Management Team on relevant health and safety activities.

2012 - 2015 Sunrise Sports Sdn. Bhd (YONEX), Klang Assistant Warehouse Manager

- Manage all aspects of warehouse operations which includes picking, packing and organizing storage area for need and easy retrieval.
- Manage inventory control, storage, retrieval and timely delivery of goods, shipment loading and transferring, document recording and data entry into system in accuracy and timely manner.
- Supervise and coordinate with forwarders, movers and contractors on the fast and save delivery.
- Work with store supervisor and manage inventory stocks and data to ensure all requests and orders are delivered smoothly.
- Maintain physical condition of warehouse by planning and implementing new design layouts, inspecting equipment, issuing work orders for repair and requisitions for replacement
- Achieves operational objectives by contributing information and recommendations to strategic plans and reviews, preparing and completing action plans, implementing productivity & quality plans as well as completing audits.
- Ensure first-in-first-out policy
- Support and operate in-house inventory system
- Coordinate with related HOD regarding data update control records.
- Liaise closely with production, planning and external parties

2009 - 2012

Scicom Msc Berhad, Kuala Lumpur

HR Executive - Industrial Relation/Employee Relations

- To investigate and verify disciplinary issues and provide counseling and coaching to staffs who have committed wrong doings or misbehaved.
- To prepare expatriate staffs' working permits and Visa by liaising with MDEC and Immigration.
- To manage the welfare needs of expatriate staffs' accommodations and to deal with apartment owners regarding Tenancy Agreements and also damages matter.
- Manage and recruit stags on all matters including government requirements (EPF, Socso, LHDN, etc;)
- Prepare and submit monthly HSE and accommodation for monthly review by Management and Payroll department.
- Conduct training and HSE orientation for staffs.

2004 - 2009

Cyneergy Solutions & Services, Klang

Training Officer

- Provide orientation and training to employees to maintain a safe and secure work environment.
- Identify training and development needs through job analysis, appraisal schemes and regular consultation with managers and human resources departments
- Design and expand training and development programs based on the needs of the company and the individuals
- Monitor and review the progress of trainees through surveys and discussions with managers
- To produce training materials for in-house courses
- To manage the delivery of training and development programs
- Keep up to date with developments in training by reading relevant journals, going to meetings and attending relevant courses

2002 - 2004

KPS Metal Trading

Admin / Operation Executive

- Preparation & Submission of KDN applications
- In-charge of all immigration matters related to the foreign workers, renewal, passport renewal, FOMEMA, Medical checkup.
- Liaison with the Agent's for the supply of foreign workers.
- Daily operation activity of projects & liaison
- Handle staff placement & operational matters & disciplinary matters.
- Preparation of attendance of staff for salary calculation.

EDUCATION

2012-2013 : Professional Diploma in Freight Logistics Management &

Operations, Open University Malaysia

2009 : Safety & Health Officer Programme, National Institute of

Occupational Safety & Health (NIOSH), Bangi

SKILLS

Microsoft Office

• Auto CAD

- Windows Professional XP and 7
- Factory & Machinery Act 1967
- Occupation Safety & Health Act 1994
- Forklift & Overhead Crane Training

LANGUAGES

• Written: Bahasa Melayu and English

• Spoken: Bahasa Melayu, English and Tamil

ADDITIONAL INFO

- Date of Availability March 2017 onwards
- Expected Salary RM4000 (negotiable)
- Willing to travel (100%)
- Own transport

REFERENCES

- Ms.Uma Devi HR Manager SMPC Industries 016-216 5110
- Mr. David Vishu Thamboe HR Senior Specialist Scicom MSC Bhd 019-668 8488
- Sheyma Ranggasamy Managing Director Cyneergy Solutions & Services 019 214 4855